Rin Phanith (Miss.)

Address : Ronass village, SangkatKohDach, Khan Rusey Koe, Phnom Penh.

(+855) 81 736 666 /093 22 09 78 / rinphanit6666@gmail.com

Bitus E&C

Address: SSN Building 4th Floor, Norodom Blvd., Sangkat Chey Chomnas,

Khan Daun Penh, Phnom Penh.

E-mail : hr@bitusenc.com
Tel : 023 980 280

Position apply for : Assistant accountant

09-March-2017

Dear Sir or Madam:

I was very pleased when I read the announcement which posted in the website www.aseanhr.com about **Assistant accountant** Requirements. I was so interested with this job vacancy. So, I would like to apply for this positioning your company.

I believe that my skill-sets, education, experiences and my unique personality are suitable with your job requirements. I have worked as accountant at Hyundai Xteer Co., Ltd for more than two year and a half, as customer service officer and receptionist for HGB Auto Co., Ltd (Mazda Showroom) for more than one years, waitress for Kolarb Penh Chit Restaurant. As accountant, customer service officer and receptionist, I handled all accounting matter and customer need and others matters in the company.

I have more than two years experiences in accounting and customer service officer and receptionist for customer need. I am capable for problem solving in various fields and excellent presentation skills that make me able to deliver the information properly. I am also able to use English language. So I hope that I can do this job well if you give me this great opportunity because I am very active, creative, hardworking, open minded person, quickly and willing to learn new thing, pleasant, flexible especially honesty person and friendly, good at preparing and good communication and work well in teamwork and can work under pressure.

I attached my resume along this letters to describe my detailed abilities and experiences for you. Please kindly contact me at (+855)81 736 666 or (+855)93 220 978 or by e-mail: rinphanit6666@gmail.com in your convenience times for interviewing me. I am looking forward to hear from you. Thank you for considering my application.

Yours sincerely

Rin Phanit

CURRICULUM VITAE

Miss. RIN PHANIT

Address: Ronass Village, Sangkat Koh Dach, Khan Russey keo, Phnom Penh

Tel : 081 736 666 / 093 22 09 78 E-mail : <u>Phanit6666@gmail.com</u>



-Name and Surname : RIN PHANIT

-Sex : Female

-Date of Birth : February/ 05th /1990

-Nationality : Khmer -Marital Status : Married

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

-Oct-2013 - Present : Studying Bachelor of Accounting at Panha Ckiet University (PCU)

-2011-2013 : Graduated Bac II at Prek Leap High school. -2008-2011 : Graduated Diploma at Preak Leap high school

WORK EXPERIENCES

- 2014-Present : Working as accountant for Hyundai Xteer Co., Ltd

+ Duties and responsibilities:

1. Account Receivable (A/R)

- o Perform daily check purchase order (PO) from sales team
- o Perform daily check products price in PO to make sure the price in PO is same with system. If not same, need to verify with sales team and need approval from general manager (GM).
- o Perform daily issue & post Invoice to System
- o Filling account documents
- o Manage customer list and control account receivable.
- O Perform daily check account receivable (A/R) report
- o Perform daily call & follow-up collection payment from customer
- Prepare payment documents (Invoice, Delivery Note and PO) for sales team to collect payment from customers
- Collect payment from sales team in cash/ cheque and compare with A/R report.
- o Perform daily received payment into system
- o Prepare daily payment collection report to account Manager
- Deposit payment collection into bank
- Prepare monthly account receivable (A/R) statement

2. Account Payable (A/P)

 $\overline{}$

- Perform daily check all requests payment documents from other department to make sure all support documents, Purchase Request (PR), Quotation, Purchase Order (PO), Invoice, Receive Item Note (RN) and other supporting documents is enough to make payment.
- o Check the quantity and price of received goods based on the purchase order and invoice.
- O Check payment term of supplier or requester



- o Perform daily payment planning and release payment to supplier
- Prepare Petty Cash Voucher (PV) or Bank Voucher (BV) & Cheque for manager to get approval from accounting manager.
- After that, all payments request approved by Account Manager and GM, Payable will make payment for supplier and requester
- o Register payment to system
- o Manage petty cash spending and replenishment.
- o Control advance payment report
- o Perform monthly stock count as per assigned
- o Prepare monthly payable report and submit to Chief Accountant.
- o Provide support to all type of audits/visits and tax submission.
- o Provide assistance to month end closing.
- Maintain files and documentation thoroughly and accurately, in accordance with company policy and accepted accounting practices
- o Report the tasks to account manager.
- Do other task as required by management team

- Apr, 2012 – 2014 : Worked as customer service and receptionist for HGB Auto., Ltd

- + Duties and responsibilities:
 - Answer incoming phone call
 - Obtain new clients by customer's contacts (in-bound)
 - o take full care of the client's requests and needs by e-mail & phone
 - Pay attention to high quality of customer service
 - Create good company image on the local market
 - o Get customer's information from sales team
 - o Report to management

2008-2011 : Worked as a waitress for Kolarb Penh Chit Restaurant

LANGUAGE

- Khmer : Excellent speaking, writing, listening reading

- English : Speak, Read, Listen, Write

COMPUTER COURSE

-Computer course : Microsoft word and Excel

- Internet : Internet, E-mail, Outlook and other

- Social Network : Facebook, line, Viber, Whatsapp, Telegram...etc.

HOBBIES

-Free time : Like doing homework, reading book, watching TV, facebook, search

Internet...etc.

REFFERENCE

-Mr. Heang Vantha : Finance and Accounting Manager at Hyundai Xteer Co., Ltd.

H/P: 089 830 003

- Mr. Lok Sony : Admin and HR manager at K Four Group Ltd.

H/P: 095 666 716

-Mr. Sronn Mengsong : The lecturer of accounting at Panha Cheit University

H/P: 098 667 242